Guide to the Consolidation Coal Company Records, 1854-1971 AIS.2011.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Predecessor & Subsidiary Companies' Minute Books, III.
  - Massillon Coal Mining Company, 96.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No. 2, June 12, 1907-August 14, 1917
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No. 3, August 18, 1917-May 22, 1928
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No. 4, January 23, 1929-Ocotber 1, 1930 (Box 21)
  - Metropolitan Coal Company, 97.
    Incorporated: April 28, 1898, in Mass.; Demised: Unknown. Sold out of Consolidation Coal Company family in 1940; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Owned waterfront coal terminals in Boston, Mass. Became subsidiary of Consolidation Coal Company in Nov. 1903. Common stock acquired by Pittston Company ca. 1930. Preferred stock sold in 1940.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 16, 1904-March 2, 1923 (Box 21)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 6, 1923-October 29, 1940
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings-Index
  - Midland Coal Company, 98.
    Incorporated: May 3, 1900, in Pa.; Demised: dissolved January 4, 1943; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Washington County, Pa. Assets sold to Pittsburgh Coal Company in 1912.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 5, 1900-January 19, 1942 (Box 21)
  - Milwaukee-Western Fuel Company, 99.
    Incorporated: March 25, 1941, in Wisc.; Demised: Dissolved July 23, 1946; Predecessor: None; Successor: North Western-Hanna Fuel Company; Statistics: Acquired by Pittsburgh Coal Company in 1923. Operated coal docks on Great Lakes. Upon dissolution, transferred all property and assets to North Western-Hanna Fuel Company, owner of all outstanding shares of capital stock.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 31, 1916-December 20, 1927 (Box 21)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 10, 1928-March 26, 1941
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 8, 1941-June 23, 1946
  - Milwaukee Western Steamship Company, 100.
    Incorporated: June 14, 1921, in Ohio; Demised: dissolved December 31, 1932; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated bulk carriers on Great Lakes.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, June 11, 1921-December 31, 1932 (Box 22)
  - Monga Land Company, 101.
    Incorporated: April 21, 1900, in Pa.; Demised: dissolved November 22, 1950; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Held real estate of Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company in states other than Pennsylvania.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors, April 21, 1900-June 23, 1943 (Box 22)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors, May 15, 1944-September 20, 1950
  - Monongahela Powder Company, 102.
    Incorporated: January 17, 1917, in W.Va.; Demised: dissolved May 8, 1933; Predecessor: None; Successors: Fairmont Supply Company, E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company, Atlas Powder Company; Statistics: Manufactured explosives for coal mining; subsidiary of Consolidation Coal Company; assets were divided between Fairmont Supply Company, E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company, and Atlas Powder Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No.1, January 19, 1917-February 12, 1924 (Box 22)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No.2, February 10, 1925-May 8, 1933
  - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal and Coke Company, 103.
    Incorporated: September 19, 1899, in Pa.; Demised: January 12, 1916, by merger; Predecessors: Over 90 small operators along Monongahela River; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company (Pennsylvania: 1916-1945); Statistics: Consolidation of over 90 small operators with total of over 40,000 acres of coal land. Through subsidiaries, maintained a fleet of towboats, barges, and coal yards along Ohio-Mississippi River system.
    - Minutes of Stockholders Meetings, September 19, 1899-December 31, 1915 (Box 22)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, October 10, 1899-December 1, 1903
    - Board of Directors Meetings, February 8, 1904-September 3, 1908
    - Board of Directors Meetings, October 7, 1908-February 26, 1912 (Box 23)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, March 20, 1912-December 30, 1915
    - Executive Committee Meetings, September 19, 1899-February 1, 1907
    - Executive Committee Meetings, February 13, 1907-January 12, 1910
    - Index to Minute Books of Executive Committee and Board of Directors
  - Monongahela Saw & Planing Mill Company, 104.
    Incorporated: Unknown; Demised: dissolved November 16, 1942; Predecessor: None; Successor: Monongahela Consolidated Coal and Coke Company; Statistics: Sold to Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company in October 1899.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, October 14, 1899-November 16, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Monongahela Stores Company, 105.
    Incorporated: September 16, 1949, in W.Va.; Demised: dissolved September 16, 1949; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated company store in Pursglove, W.Va.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directions, October 6, 1933-August 15, 1949 (Box 23)
  - Montana Coal and Coke Company, 106.
    Incorporated: December 8, 1886, in W.Va.; Demised: dissolved May 23, 1910; Predecessor: None; Successor: Fairmont Coal Company; Statistics: Operated coal mines in Fairmont District; property sold to Fairmont Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 1, 1887-March 6, 1899 (Box 23)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 10, 1899-May 23, 1910
  - Montour & Gregg Railway Company, 107.
    Incorporated: November 15, 1899, in Pa.; Demised: June 1909; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Charter for unbuilt railroad; controlled by Pittsburgh Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 13, 1903-September 22, 1909 (Box 23)
  - Montour Coal Company, 108.
    Incorporated: March 26, 1914, in Ill.; Demised: dissolved December 31, 1920 (Date of last meeting.); Predecessor: Illinois Collieries Company; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Macoupin County, Ill., acquired by Pittsburgh Coal Company from receivers of Illinois Collieries Company. All property sold to Pittsburgh Coal Company in August 1914.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings (Volume 37), March 26, 1914-December 30, 1920 (Oversize 104)
  - Montour Telephone Company, 109.
    Incorporated: February 17, 1903, in Pa.; Demised: stricken from record September 22, 1909; Statistics: Intended to operate telephone system in Pittsburgh Coal Company territory. Apparently inactive.
    - Minutes (Volume 38), September 28, 1906-September 22, 1909 (Oversize 104)
  - Morgantown Pittsburgh Coal Dock Company, 110.
    Incorporated: June 12, 1935, in W.Va.; Demised: dissolved January 27, 1948; Statistics: Formed to build coal terminal at Granville, W.Va.; controlled by Pursglove Coal Mining Company and Arkwright Coal Company.
    - Minutes, June 4, 1935-December 22, 1947 (Box 23)
  - Moshannon Coal Company, 111.
    Incorporated: February 25, 1870, in Pa.; Demised: dissolved October 22, 1903; Predecessor: None; Successor: Moshannon Coal & Coke Company; Statistics: Operated coal mines in the Clearfield District; property sold to Moshannon Coal & Coke Company, January 26, 1901.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 8, 1878-January 13, 1891 (Box 24)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, July 9, 1895-December 1, 1900
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, September 14, 1897-October 22, 1903
  - Mountain City Mill and Power Company, 112.
    Incorporated: November 20, 1902, in W.Va.; Demised: April 5, 1904; Predecessor: None; Successor: Fairmont & Clarksburg Traction Company; Statistics: Operated light and power plant, flour milling and general store business at Fairmont; property sold to Fairmont & Clarksburg Traction Company in 1903.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No.1, November 20, 1902-April 25, 1903 (Box 24)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings- Minute Book No.2, August 8, 1903-April 5, 1904
  - National Dock & Fuel Company, 113.
    Incorporated: October 23, 1901, in N.J.; Demised: dissolved July 28, 1905; Predecessor: Ohio Fuel Company; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Statistics: Operated coal terminals at Cleveland, Ohio; property sold to Pittsburgh Coal Company, January 1, 1903.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, October 23, 1901-July 28, 1905 (Box 24)
  - New Pittsburgh Coal Company (Delaware), 114.
    Incorporated: June 27, 1925, in Del.; Demised: ca. 1931; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Shell company intended to replace the New Pittsburgh Coal Company (Ohio); never active.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, June 27, 1925-June 25, 1931 (Box 24)
  - New Pittsburgh Coal Company (Ohio), 115.
    Incorporated: April 17, 1886, in Ohio; Demised: Unknown; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Owned 8,300 acres of coal lands in the Hocking and Pomeroy Districts of Ohio. Became subsidiary of Pittsburgh Coal Company in 1904. Absorbed Great Lakes Coal Mining Company, December 22, 1923. Property transferred to Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company, October 31, 1946.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 7, 1886-November 30, 1912 (Box 24)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 7, 1886-December 22, 1923
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 2, 1913-December 22, 1923 (Box 25)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, December 31, 1923-November 19, 1942
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, January 10, 1943-October 28, 1946
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, November 23, 1945-April 9, 1951
  - New York & Cleveland Gas Coal Company, 116.
    Incorporated: September 9, 1871, in Pa.; Demised: dissolved January 4, 1943; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Statistics: Incorporated by Carnegie interests. Operated mines southeast of Pittsburgh. Pittsburgh Coal Company acquired control in 1902. Coal operations transferred to Pittsburgh Coal Company in 1915.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, September 9, 1871-November 22, 1905 (Box 25)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 19, 1883-January 27, 1885
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, February 14, 1906-November 16, 1942
  - Northern New York Coal Company (Wisc.), 117.
    Incorporated: In Wisc. Date unknown; Demised: Unknown; Statistics: Incorporated for rail transportation of coal and coke.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, November 20, 1905-November 29, 1905 (Box 25)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 12, 1906-December 28, 1929
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 10, 1930-March 22, 1946
  - Northern New York Coal Company, Inc. (N.Y.), 118.
    Incorporated: March 13, 1935, in N.Y.; Demised: Unknown; after November 22, 1963; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated coal terminal at Watertown, N.Y. and in St. Lawrence valley. Controlled by Hanna Fuels, Inc.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, August 28, 1935-October 20, 1951 (Box 25)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 13, 1935-December 23, 1963
  - North Western Coal Railway Company, 119.
    Incorporated: 1905 in Wisc.; Demised: after 1946; Statistics: Operated short terminal railroad at Superior, Wisc. Controlled by Pittsburgh Coal Company of Wisconsin.
    - Special Meeting, November 20, 1905 (Box 26)
    - March 12, 1906-December 28, 1929
    - March 10, 1930-March 22, 1946
  - North Western Fuel Company, 120.
    Incorporated: October 28, 1901, in Wisc.; Demised: June 27, 1944; Predecessor: North Western Fuel Company (Minn.); Successor: North Western-Hanna Fuel Company; Statistics: Successor to a Minn. corporation of the same name, founded in 1871. Operated Great Lakes coal terminals and retail coal yards for Fairmont Coal Company and later Consolidation Coal Company. In October 1942, Consolidation and the M.A. Hanna Company formed a joint venture called North Western-Hanna Fuel Company, and each transferred their terminal properties to the new firm. Upon dissolution of North Western Fuel Company on June 27, 1944, all residual property and assets were transferred to Consolidation Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, October 24, 1901-April 22, 1942 (Box 26)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, September 22, 1942-June 27, 1944
  - O'Neil Coal & Coke Company, 121.
    Incorporated: July 1, 1888, in KY; Demised: dissolved November 1915; Statistics: Operated coal yards in Louisville.
    - Minutes (Volume 39), May 7, 1889-May 4, 1915 (Oversize 105)
  - Ohio Coal Company, 122.
    Incorporated: December 20, 1901, in Wisc.; Demised: dissolved December 31, 1934; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company of Wisconsin; Statistics: Operated coal terminals at Superior, Wisc. All assets conveyed to Pittsburgh Coal Company of Wisconsin in June 1906.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 12, 1906-December 31, 1934 (Box 26)
  - Ohio Valley Coal and Mining Company, 123.
    Incorporated: April 20, 1882, in Ky; Demised: dissolved January 10, 1918; Predecessor: None; Successor: Madison Coal Corporation; Statistics: Incorporated as Ohio Valley Railroad and Mining Company. Renamed Ohio Valley Coal and Mining Company March 16, 1886 and sold railroad franchise to Ohio Valley Railway Company. Operated Shotwell Mine at DeKoven, Union County, Ky. Coal property sold to Madison Coal Corporation in September 1917, and river tipple and barges sold to Pittsburgh Coal Company (Ky.)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 20, 1882-April 29, 1886 (Box 26)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 20, 1882-January 10, 1918
  - Ontario Coal and Supply Company, 124.
    Incorporated: September 28, 1910, in Pa; Demised: dissolved April 20, 1914; Predecessor: None; Successor: Saw Mill Run Coal & Supply Company; Statistics: Operated coal terminal at Ontario, Pa. Property sold to Saw Mill Run Coal & Supply Company
    - Minutes, September 28, 1910-February 9, 1914 (Box 26)
  - Owings Realty Company, 125.
    Incorporated: August 24, 1940, in W.V; Demised: dissolved December 31, 1943; Predecessor: None; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Owned surface land in Harrison County, W.Va. purchased from Consolidation Coal Company. Property reconveyed to Consolidation Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, August 24, 1940-January 17, 1944 (Box 26)
  - Palantine Coal Company, 126.
    Incorporated: November 9, 1891, in W.V; Demised: dissolved June 16, 1941; Predecessor: Newburgh Orrel Coal and Coke Company; Successor: Fairmont Coal Company; Statistics: Owned coal land in Marion County, W.Va. formerly owned and operated by Newburgh Orrel Coal and Coke Company. Property sold to Fairmont Coal Company in June 1901.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, November 9, 1891-June 16, 1941 (Box 26)
  - Pennmont Coal Company, 127.
    Incorporated: December 5, 1904, in W.V; Demised: dissolved January 11, 1911; Predecessor: None; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Somerset County, Pa. Property sold to Consolidation Coal Company, January 11, 1911.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, December 5, 1904-January 11, 1911 (Box 26)
  - Pennmont Coal Mining Company, 128.
    Incorporated: January 13, 1905, in PA; Demised: dissolved January 27, 1930; Predecessor: None; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Coal land company with property in Somerset County, Pa. Subsidiary of Consolidation Coal Company. Property sold to R. Marsden Smith in January 1911.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, December 19, 1904-January 27, 1930 (Box 27)
  - Pennois Coal and Coke Company, 129.
    Incorporated: July 27, 1899, in W.V; Demised: dissolved April 1912; Predecessor: None; Successor: Fairmont Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Fairmont District. Property sold to Fairmont Coal Company.
    - Minutes, October 17, 1899-April 8, 1912 (Box 27)
  - Pennsylvania Mining Company, 130.
    Incorporated: pre-1900, in PA; Demised: March 11, 1904 (Name change); Predecessors: New York and Cleveland Gas Coal Company, First Pool Monongahela Gas Coal Company, Mansfield Coal and Coke Company, etc.; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania; Statistics: Under agreement of January 12, 1904, the Pittsburgh Coal Company (N.J.) conveyed to the Pennsylvania Mining Company all the properties of the New York and Cleveland Coal Company, the First Pool Monongahela Gas Coal Company, the Mansfield Coal and Coke Company and all its other coal lands and railroads in Pennsylvania. Renamed Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania on March 11, 1904.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings (Volume 40)[Includes Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania], May 22, 1900-October 23, 1907 (Oversize 105)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 8, 1903-March 11, 1904 (Box 27)
  - Piercedale Supply Company, 131.
    Incorporated: September 12, 1917, in PA; Demised: dissolved December 11, 1946; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated company stores in Pa. and Ohio
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, September 12, 1917-February 11, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, February 10, 1936-December 23, 1946
  - Pike-Floyd Coal Company, 132.
    Incorporated: August 19. 1910, in Ohio; Demised: dissolved October 31, 1946; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Owned 227 acres of coal land in eastern Kentucky. Property and assets sold to the Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company on October 31, 1946.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, June 18, 1944-October 31, 1946 (Box 27)
  - Pioneer Fuel Company (Wisc.), 133.
    Incorporated: April 12, 1901, in Wisc.; Demised: dissolved December 31, 1934; Predecessor: Pioneer Fuel Company (Minn.); Successor: None; Statistics: Operated coal terminal at Duluth, Minn. Subsidiary of Pittsburgh Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, April 12, 1901-April 30, 1901 (Box 27)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, November 20, 1905-November 29, 1905 (Box 28)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, March 12, 1906-December 31, 1934
  - Pittsburgh & Castle Shannon Railroad, 134.
    Incorporated: September 18, 1871, in PA; Demised: Unknown; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Railways Company; Statistics: Built railroad of 3'-4" narrow gauge from Pittsburgh to Castle Shannon with branch to coal mines. Opened November 1, 1871. Leased to Pittsburgh Railways system, September 1, 1905, and converted to trolley line.
    - Minutes, June 26, 1878-November 20, 1880 (Box 28)
  - Pittsburgh & Chicago Gas Coal Company, 135.
    Incorporated: 1883 in PA; Demised: dissolved April 7, 1914; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pennsylvania Mining Company; Statistics: Incorporated by Pitcairn family. Purchased by Pittsburgh Coal Company and all property transferred to Pennsylvania Mining Company in October 1901.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 1, 1895-April 7, 1914 (Box 28)
  - Pittsburgh & Eastern Coal Company, 136.
    Incorporated: December 15, 1903, in PA; Demised: dissolved December 30, 1933; Successor: Cherry Valley Coal Mining Company; Statistics: Owned and mined 2,500 acres of coal land in Washington County, Pa. Organized by the Hanna interests. Assets sold to Cherry Valley Coal Mining Company in December 1933.
    - Agreement Book, June 30, 1903-October 11, 1932 (Box 28)
    - Minute Book No.1, January 19, 1903-February 14, 1907
    - Minute Book No.2, May 20, 1907-January 21, 1916
    - Minute Book No.3, February 8, 1916-December 27, 1933
  - Pittsburgh and Fairmont Fuel Company, 137.
    Incorporated: February 2, 1903, in W.V; Demised: dissolved October 15, 1912; Successor: Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Operated mines in Fairmont District. Acquired by Fairmont Coal Company July 27, 1904.
    - Minute Book (Volume 41), May 12, 1903-April 15, 1912 (Oversize 105)
  - Pittsburgh and Fairmont Packet Company, 138.
    Incorporated: May 18, 1909, in W.V; Demised: dissolved May 29, 1913; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Operated steamboat on Monongahela River.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, May 18, 1909-May 29, 1913 (Box 28)
  - Pittsburgh Coal Car Company, 139.
    Incorporated: March 23, 1904, in PA; Demised: dissolved June 11, 1914; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania; Statistics: Owned fleet of railroad coal cars. Subsidiary of Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania.
    - Minutes of Board of Directors and Stockholders Meetings, April 18, 1904-June 11, 1914 (Box 28)
  - Pittsburgh Coal Carbonization Company, 140.
    Incorporated: August 8, 1932, in DE; Demised: dissolved September 11, 1946; Predecessor: None; Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Manufactured domestic heating smokeless fuel briquettes by distillation of coal. Sold under trade name "Disco." Joint venture with the Illingworth Carbonization Company, Limited of U.K. Held U.S. patents for Illingworth process of low-temperature carbonization of coal and a plant built by Pittsburgh Coal Company. Upon dissolution, property and assets transferred to Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, August 6, 1932-September 11, 1946 (Box 28)
  - Pittsburgh Coal Company, Inc., 141.
    Incorporated: April 4, 1927, in N.Y.; Demised: dissolved December 6, 1946; Predecessor: Pittsburgh Coal Company; Successor: Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company; Statistics: Operated Buffalo sales agency for Pittsburgh Coal Company.
    - Minutes (cracking spine), April 4, 1927-December 6, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Pittsburgh Coal Company of Illinois, 1905-1920; 142.
    Incorporated: November 27, 1905, in IL; Demised: dissolved December 31, 1920; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Acquired and operated Pittsburgh Coal Company's Chicago sales agency.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, November 4, 1905-January 6, 1911 (Box 6)
  - Pittsburgh Coal Company of Illinois, 1923-1942; 143.
    Incorporated: December 31, 1923, in IL; Demised: dissolved December 4, 1942; Predecessor: None; Successor: None; Statistics: Acquired and operated Pittsburgh Coal Company's Chicago sales agency. Office closed in 1926.
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Board of Directors Meetings, December 22, 1923-December 4, 1942 (Box 7)
  - Pittsburgh Coal Company (Kentucky), 144.